A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich and Martha Marquardt papers (Wellcome collection) FA136
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Martha Marquardt Material, 2
  - Correspondance
    - Knecht, Josef, 1952; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Koch, Richard, 1922-1931; 37 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kolle, Willhelm, 1922; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
      copy of Kolle to Heinsheimer Martha Marquardt's
    - Kolle, Willhelm (Box 10, Folder 3)
      lawyer regarding her dismissal from the institute
    - Kölnische Illustrierte Zeitung, 1933; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Konzelmann, Max, 1930; 8 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kossel, Hermann, 1921 1924; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kra, Helen, 1949; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kress, Hubert, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kronfeld, Adolf, 1936; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kruger, Else, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Krupp von Bohlen und Halbach, 1921; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kyes, Preston, 1921 1951; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Landau, Marianne, 1921-1956; 60 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Landwirtschaftskammer für Hessen, 1929-1930; 6 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lancet, The, 1924-1946; 5 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lange, Gertrude and Dr.?, 1929-1932; 12 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lange, Tonnjes, 1948; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lasassagne, A., 1931; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Laubenheimer, (August's son), 1947 1948; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lautenschlager, C. L., 1930; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lazarus, Adolph, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - League of Nations, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lehmann, Julius, 1923; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lehmanns, Verlag, 1948; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Leigh, Florence, 1951; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Leipzig University, 1950; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lennhoff, Eugen, 1930; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lenz, Kurt, 1929-1933; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Leupold, Frida, 1915 June 11 1915 August 11 1924; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Levaditi, Constantin, 1931-1952; 23 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Leverkusen Chemische Werke, 1948; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lewinsohn, H., 1933; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Liljestrand, G., 1947; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lillingston, Claude, 1931; 5 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lilly, Eli and Company, 1945 1951; 6 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lindauersche Buchhandlung, 1947; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Linser, 1930-1931; 8 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lisbon School of Tropical Medicine, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Loeb, Jacques, 1921 1922; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Loraine, John A., 1950; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lorentz, Heinrich, 1929-1930; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lowenfeld, Margaret, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lustig, Arthur, 1946-1951; 27 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Madsen, Thorvald, 1924; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mannheimer, George, 1924; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mannheimer, J., 1922-1933; 14 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McCumm, 1949; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Medical Research Council, 1950-1954; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Medicin Inspecteur Général, 1931; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - die Medizinische Welt, 1929-1931; 15 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Meerfeld, 1932; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Meijer, H. W., 1949; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Meltzer, 1921; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mendel, Victor, 1929; 8 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mensenkampff, von, 1930; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Messner, Franz, 1943; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Metro Goldwyn-Mayer, 1931-1932; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Metz, Herman A., 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Michaelis, Hedwig and Leonor, 1949; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mielke Family, 1930-1939; 11 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Miller, J., 1949; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Millington, S. W., 1954 1956; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mobus, Thilla, 1924-1930; 5 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mohr, Hildegard, 1929-1934; 23 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Moller, Knud Max, 1954; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Montizambert, E., 1935 1938; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Morgenroth, Julius, 1918-1923; 8 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mühlen, Walrat von, 1932 1950; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Müller, Otto, 1934; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Münchner Illustrierte, 1932-1933; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Münchner Medizinisch Wochenschau, 1924 1951-1952; 5 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Muni, Paul, 1939; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Muntendam, P., 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Murphy, Robert, 1933; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Nachmann, 1932; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Nagel, E., 1948; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Naumann, (typewriter service), 1931-1932; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Neue Züricher Zeitung, 1930; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Nordensen, undated; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Neisser, Max, 1924-1930; 6 letters (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Neufeld, F, 1933; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Neuste Forschung, 1931; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Novy, Fritz, 1951; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Olden, Rudolf, 1937; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Oppersdorf, Graf, 1932; 28 letters (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Ostenvander, 1923; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Otto, Richard, 1924-1947; 20 letters (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Oxenius, 1929-1930; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Pabst, Gustav, 1932 1946; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Painleve, Jean, 1931-1936; 19 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Paneuropa Verlag, undated; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pange, Jean de, 1932 1933; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Park, 1922; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pastre, H., 1931; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pathé Cinéma, 1930-1933; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pergamon Press, 1953-1956; 48 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pfannenstiel, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pinkus, Felix, 1924 1947; 6 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Pinkus, Hermann, 1950-1956; 17 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Polizei Präsidium, 1929; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Poncet, François, 1933; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Portig, Felix, 1949; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Postamt, Frankfurt, 1930; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Prüm Hospital, 1949; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Radcliffe Science Library, 1949; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Raff, Friedrich, 1929; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Raschke, Margarete, 1932; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Reichsversicherungsanstalt Berlin, 1931; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Richter, Emma, 1947-1949; 5 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rieber Publishing House, 1947; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rieckmann, Oswald, 1930-1933; 7 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Riesenfeld, E. H., 1931; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Ritter, Pater, 1930; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Robotsky, O., 1929-1933; 5 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rondoni, Pietro, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rosbaud, P., 1948-1953; 21 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Royal Institute of Public Health and Hygiene, 1946; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Royal Microscopic Society, 1949; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Royal Society, The, 1949; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Royal Veterinary College, 1947; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rucker, Pierce, 1951; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rummel, Walter and Frau, 1930-1931; 8 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Rustinsches Lehrinstitute, 1931; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Sachs, Hans, 1921-1922; 19 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sagan, Leontine, 1932; 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Salon de Cinema, 1930; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Salomonsen, Carl, 1921-1924; 6 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Säuglings-und Kleinkinderschutz, 1929; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schamoni, Victor, 1929-1933; 13 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Scharp, Heinrich, 1929-1933; 19 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Scharr, 1929; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Scheffer, Paul, 1929; 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schleicher und Schull, 1923; 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schlemmer, Clare and Alen, 1931-1933; 5 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schlossberger, Hans, 1924-1956; 55 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schmidt, Herta, 1946-1949; 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schmitz, Paul, 1931-1932; 4 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schneider, Carl, 1947; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schott, Alice, 1924; 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schramm, 1929; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schubert, Cäcilie, 1954; 6 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schuckmann, von, 1929; 6 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schulz, Anna, 1922; 4 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schuman, Henry Publishing House, 1950-1954; 33 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schütz, Eberhard, 1945; 8 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Schütz, Ellen, 1949-1955; 13 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Schütz, Erna, 1945-1949; 234 letters (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Schütz, Erna, 1950-1956 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Schütz, Franzi, 1929-1950; 29 letters (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Schütz, Otti, 1933; 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Schwabacher, Ernst, 1930; 5 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Schwartz, Philipp, 1938; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Schweitzer Illustrierte, 1933; 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Schwerin, Ernst, 1924-1933; 3 letters (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Schwerin, Hans, 1924-1956; 48 letters (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Schwerin, Günther, 1947-1955; 37 letters (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Schwerin, Stefanie, 1924-1956; 91 letters (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Seligo, Hans, 1932; 9 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Shiga, Kiyoshi, 1909-1950; 19 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Simon, Heinrich, 1922-1923; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sinzheimer, 1924; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sluiter, 1950; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Helen, 1950; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Theobald, 1921 1922; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Social Hygiene Office, Paris, 1929; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Société Immobiliere, 1932; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Société Parisienne d'Exploitations Cinématographiques, 1930-1931; 25 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Springer Verlag, 1921-1952; 98 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Staudermann, Will, 1947; 7 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sternthal, Friedrich, 1938; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Stoetzer, W., 1948; 5 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Stracey-Cheel, S. M. (secretary to Sir Henry Dale), 1954-1956; 27 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Strauss, Jenny, 1924; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Strödler, Helene, 1924; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Strubberg, von, 1929; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Stühmer, A., 1954; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Südwestdeutscher Rundfunk, 1929-1930; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Süddeutsches Monatsheft, 1921; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sugnet, Berthe, 1932 1933; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sundberg, Carl, 1921-1922; 6 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Supfle, 1930; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Surkamp, Ernst, 1948; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tagebuch Publishing House, 1932; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tarbes, 1940; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tasch, 1929; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tedesco, Jean, 1931; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Telegraphen Union, 1930; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Thomass, Marie, 1947; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Thormann, 1931-1933; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Times, The London, 1935 1946; 6 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tourist Center, French, 1936; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Treuherz, Walter, 1939-1950; 24 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tribout, Liliane, 1950; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Trouillas, Gertrud, 1933-1950; 18 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Tübingen University, 1948; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ullstein Verlag, 1929-1932; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Underwood, Ashworth, 1946-1951; 29 letters (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Urban und Schwarzenberg, 1948; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Velhagen und Klasing Monatshefte, 1932-1933; 16 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Vimont, 1930; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Vossische Zeitung, 1930; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wagner Family, 1934; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Warburg, Otto, 1956; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Warner Brothers, 1939-1953; 47 letters (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Waugh, Grant, 1949-1954; 7 letters (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weber, 1929-1933; 5 letters (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Wechselmann, 1924; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weigert, Karl, 1951; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weinberg, Arthur von, 1924-1933; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weinreich, W., 1924; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Weil, Ernst, 1923-1941; 147 letters (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Weil, Ernst, 1944-1956 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Weizmann, Chaim, original letter, 1950; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Welch, William, 1921; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wellcome Foundation, 1954; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Weltbühne, 1932; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wertheimer, 1933; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Westermanns Monatshefte, 1932; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Whites and Taylors, 1951; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wild, George, 1930-1931; 6 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Williamson, Harold, 1933; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Windecker, Carl, 1931-1932; 10 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Winslow, William, 1953; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Winthrobe, M. M., 1954; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wittkopf, 1929; 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wolf, Franz, 1924-1933; 7 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Woodhouse, 1951; 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Wright, Sir Almroth, 1906-1947; 136 letters (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Zeiss, H., 1929-1931; 4 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Zeiss, Ikon Ag, 1932-1933; 6 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Zerwer, Toni, 1929-1933; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Zierkow, Paul, 1948; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Zimmermann, K., 1938; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Zinnemann, Kurt, 1939; 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified senders, 17 letters (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Picture Postcards, About 200 picture postcards (Box 13)
  - Photographs, About 100 photographs, some in frames (Box 14)
    Many photographs of Martha Marquardt at various times.
  - Martha Marquardt's curriculum vitae (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Martha Marquardt's curriculum vitae and autobiographical notes; 3 in German, 1 in English. 1 paper clipping about Martha Marquardt in the Auckland Star, New Zealand.
  - Martha Marquardt's book "Paul Ehrlich als Mensch und Arbeiter", Reviews and related articles
    - Printer's copy of Paul Ehrlich als Mensch und Arbeiter, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Reviews of book: Paper clippings (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Reviews of national medical journals, 9 items (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - One scrapbook of reviews (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - International reviews of book, printed in 10 medical journals (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Review of Paul de Kruif's "Microbe Hunters", 1927 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Articles written by Martha Marquardt: (Paper clippings) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Nachdenkliches von Unterwegs - Südfrankreich", 1926; 15 pages. 3 copies and 3 typewritten pages of notes, complete typewritten manuscript
    - "Nie wieder langer Rock", 1929
    - "Wie man aus der Fliege - Elefanten macht", 1929
    - "Die Technische Assistentin", 1929
    - "Stätten deutscher Kultur in Paris", 1931
    - "Mit Haut und Haaren", 1933
    - "Entlarvte Menschenfeinde", 1933
    - "Dreissig Jahre Film", no date
    - "Eine Fliege = 40 Millionen Elefanten", undated
  - Articles and Photographs by Martha Marquardt (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - 5 typewritten articles by Martha Marquardt and photographs of anatomical sections, flies, hair, etc.
    - "Unsere Glücksfliege oder 1 Fliege = 40 Millionen Elefanten"
    - "Wir atmen - wir leben"
    - "Unsere Sonne"
    - "Mit Haut und Haaren"
    - "Die Fliege als Krankheitsüberträgerin"
  - Photographs taken by Martha Marquardt, 2 albums with pictures of microscopic sections (Box 15, Folder 8, Folder 9)
  - Various paper clippings (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Scrapbook of paper clippings - 1928, of various political articles, 1925- which appeared in the "Rhein - Mainische Volkszeitung". Some may have been translated by Martha Marquardt.
  - Martha Marquardt's articles about Paul Ehrlich in 1929, 1 typescript copy, 8 reprints (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Martha Marquardt's article at the occasion of Paul Ehrlich's 75th birthday.
  - Essays by Martha Marquardt, 19 short essays, all typescript (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Ein wahres Erlebnis", 1 page
    - "Der Sieg des Dichters", 1 paper clipping of article, 2 pages
    - "Protection of Wood from Decay", 3 pages
      8 copies of letters to newspapers, offering this article for publication.
    - "Artificially Produced Pearls", 5 pages
    - "Wool that will not get moth-eaten", 3 pages
    - "Sick Teeth the Cause of Internal Diseases", 2 pages
    - "Radium and Precious Stones", 3 pages
    - "Der Zerfall des Radiums und die Wirksame Energie, welche bei diesem Zerfall frei wird", 20 pages
    - "Zerfall und Aktivitatsverlauf des Mesothors", 2 pages
    - "The Role of Aluminum in the Life of Organisms", 3 pages
    - "Colloidal Sulfur an Agent to Combat Insects and Larvae Pernicious to Plants", 1 page
    - "Gaining Small-Coal by Means of Sucking off the Coal-Dust", 1 page
    - "Catherinetten", 2 pages
    - "Gestöhlen", 6 pages
    - "Schönheit", 3 pages
    - "Der 'erzieherische Wert', der studentischen Korporation", 2 pages
    - "Stilblüten", 4 pages
    - "Diplomatischer Nachwuchs?", 2 pages
    - "Synopsis", 7 pages
  - "Fly" - film: Film made by Martha Marquardt entitled "Gefährliche Plagegeister" (Flies in english and La Mouche in French) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 3 copies of scenarios, one each in English, French and German
    - 6 licenses to show the film as an educational film
    - 15 paper clippings of film reviews and announcements
    - 5 typewritten pages of transcripts of newspaper reviews
  - Various plays by Martha Marquardt
    - Play written by Martha Marquardt, "Das Telefon und die Grippe", typewritten manuscript, 35 pages (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Die Kleinen Leute von Paris", softcover copy of Martha Marquardt's book, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 14 reviews of 'Die Kleinen Leute von Paris", paper clippings, 10 typewritten pages of transcriptions of reviews which appeared in various papers. 8 typewritten pages of transcriptions of opinions by friends about "Die Kleinen Leute von Paris". (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Album: Deutsche Köpfe (Folder 5)
    "Deutsche Köpfe", Eine Gabe für den Deutschen Hilfsverein, Paris, 11 Januar 1930; folder containing photographs of 9 prominent Germans each with a quotation.
  - Goethe - Celebration, 1932 (Folder 6)
    "Goethe - Celebration", 30 paper clippings and articles about the Goethe celebration in Germany and France.
  - Paul Ehrlich Prize Invitations, 1930-1931; 3 items (Folder 7)
    Paul Ehrlich Prize; invitations to 1930 and 1931 Paul Ehrlich Prize ceremonies.
  - Martha Marquardt articles about Paul Ehrlich, 1934 1939 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    This folder contains English, French and German articles written by Martha Marquardt on the occasion of Ehrlich's 80th and 85th birthdays. She sent these articles to various publishing houses and in addition to the typescript copies of these articles, there is correspondence with the publishing houses, as well as some paper clippings.
  - Movie material: Dr. Ehrlich's Magic Bullet: "Dr. Ehrlich's Magic Bullet", 1939 Warner Bros. movie material
    - 3 contracts between Warner Bros., Martha Marquardt and Deutsche Verlags-Austalkt Stuttgart (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 10 receipts and notes regarding material sent (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Comments about the movie, presumably by Hans Schwerin, grandson of Paul Ehrlich, 1 typescript copy (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 10 newspaper clippings of movie reviews (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Pages by Martha Marquardt to be used for the movie script, About 150 typewritten pages (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Martha Marquardt visit to Frankfurt, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    13 typewritten pages of Martha Marquardt's account of her trip to Frankfurt in search of any surviving Paul Ehrlich material, mainly reprints of his scientific publications.
  - 2 Radio Shows (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - 2 science radio programs produced by the British Broadcasting Corporation in 1936, 1946
    - "Operation 606", 5 copies of transcripts
    - "Operation Painless", 2 copies of transcripts
  - Material dealing with the book: Paul Ehrlich (Box 17)
    Martha Marquardt's enlarged version of her book on Paul Ehrlich. After her book "Paul Ehrlich als Mensch und Arbeiter" was published in 1924, she worked on a more detailed account of Paul Ehrlich's life. The German manuscript was finished during the war years in Paris. When she arrived in London she translated this German version into English. The English book was published in 1949 by William Heinemann Medical Books Ltd. The German book was published in 1951 by Springer Verlag. Sir Henry Dale wrote a foreword which appeared in both versions.
    - Enlarged version, in English, entitled "Paul Ehrlich" by Martha Marquardt, 215 pages, typewritten manuscript (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Author's copy of proof (Box 17, Folder 2)
      German version, a few pages are missing. 45 printers copies of photographs used in the book.
    - German version of Sir Henry Dale's introduction, 14 typewritten pages; Martha Marquardt's introduction in German, 3 typewritten pages (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Appendix" (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Remarks on Paul Ehrlich and his work by friends and contemporaries - 121 typewritten pages by Martha Marquardt. "Anhang" - same as above, in German, 14 typewritten pages.
    - Notes by Martha Marquardt about the English and German versions of her book, 27 typewritten pages (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Reviews of Martha Marquardt's book "Paul Ehrlich" (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Paper clippings and articles in various journals, including The Lancet, Saturday Review, The Jewish Monthly, British Journal of Venereal Diseases and Therapeutische Umschau..
  - Material dealing with "The Collected papers of Paul Ehrlich"
    - "Vorwort", 1877-1915 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      16 typewritten pages, describing Martha Marquardt's endeavors to have Paul Ehrlich's scientific papers published as a collection. Bibliography: 38 typewritten pages with many corrections covering the years 1877 to 1915. This may be a complete bibliography of Paul Ehrlich.
    - Paul Ehrlich's bibliography (Box 17, Folder 8)
      Many typewritten pages and handwritten notes regarding Paul Ehrlich's bibliography.
    - Various lists of addresses, some of personal friends of Martha Marquardt. Some of the lists were compiled to request financial support for a publication of Paul Ehrlich's collected papers, before the Wellcome Trust gave a grant for this publication (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Karl Weigert material, 1845-1904 1956 1957 1959 (Box 17, Folder 10)